[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
Okay, this is exciting.
حسنًا، هذا شيق.
We reminded ourselves of gradient descent and what that looks like.
لقد ذكرنا أنفسنا بالنزول التدريجي وكيف يشبه ذلك.
We figured out what the discretion model is.
وتعرفنا على نموذج الانحدار اللوجستي
We talked about maximum likelihood functions and estimation.
وتحدثنا عن أقصى الاحتمالات كما تعاملنا مع الدوال واستعنا التقديرات.
And we can solve quite a bit of the math.
كما يمكننا حل الكثير من المعادلات.
Now, lets dive in and look at the actual learning algorithm for
الآن، دعونا نتعمق أكثر وننظر إلى خوارزمية التعلم الفعلية
logistic regression.
للانحدار اللوجستي.
That learning algorithm's going to be extremely simple.
ستكون خوارزمية التعلم المذكورة بسيطة للغاية.
And so, in spite of the math we've seen, we are going to come up algorithm that you
فعلى الرغم من المعادلات التي رأيناها، سوف نتعامل مع خوارزمية
can implement in just a couple lines of code.
يمكن تنفيذها فقط في بضعة أسطر من الكود.
To, this final graded ascent algorithm for logistic regression,
وخوارزمية الصعود النهائي التدريجي للانحدار اللوجستي،
all we have to do is fine the derivative, with respect to each parameter, wj.
كل ما يتعين علينا القيام به هو إيجاد المشتق بالنسبة لكل متغير wj.
So what's the derivative for likelihood function with respect to wj?
إذن ما هو المشتق لدالة الاحتمال بالنسبة إلى wj؟
By the way, this derivatives side note,
بالمناسبة، هذه الملاحظة الجانبية المشتقة،
going to be of the log of the likelihood function, the log likelihood.
ستكون في لوغاريتم دالة الاحتمال، أو لوغاريتم الاحتمالية.
And I'll explain a little bit more why that is,
وسأوضح أكثر سبب ذلك،
in an advanced section of this module later on, an optional one.
في قسم متقدم من هذه الوحدة لاحقًا، وسيكون اختياريًا.
But just think about it as a derivative of the likelihood for now.
ولكن فكر في الأمر على أنه مشتق الاحتمالية في الوقت الحالي.
Now, the derivative of the likelihood is going to be equal to the sum
الآن، سيكون المشتق من الاحتمالية مساويًا للمجموع
over the data points, so we're going to consider that each data point has
على نقاط البيانات، لذلك سنعتبر أن كل نقطة بيانات
a contribution to the derivative, some only want to make the derivative big,
مساهمة في المشتق، بعضها يزيد من حجم المشتق،
some like to make the derivative smaller, but we're going to sum over the data
والبعض الآخر يقلل من حجم المشتق، لكننا سنجمع على نقاط البيانات
points of the difference between what's called the indicator function that
من الفرق بين ما يسمى وظيفة المؤشر
a data point is plus 1, so indicator of whether this data point is positive.
التي تشير إلى أن النقطة هي +1، أو هو المؤشر لما إذا كانت نقطة البيانات المذكورة إيجابية.
So I'm going to specify it at the bottom here.
لذا سأقوم بتحديدها في الأسفل هنا.
So let's get our ink.
دعونا نحصل على الحبر.
So this indicated function simply say output 1 if
إذن، هذه الوظيفة المشار إليها تفترض ببساطة أن المخرج 1
yi is truly a positive example.
إذا كان yi مثالًا إيجابيًا فعلًا.
And output 0 if yi is a negative example.
وتقوم بإخراج 0 إذا كانت yi مثالًا سلبيًا.
So that's the indicator is.
هذا هو المؤشر.
So this is this definition over here.
هذا هو التعريف هنا.
So is this a positive example?
وبالتالي هذا مثال إيجابي
And the second term, so there's a difference between that and
والمصطلح الثاني، لذلك هناك فرق بين ذلك وبين ما يتنبأ به النموذج،
whatever my model predicts,
.
that how much my model thus far predict, that xi is positive.
وكمية ما يتوقعه النموذج الخاص بي حتى الآن، بأن xi إيجابي.
In other words, if this is the difference between the truth, is this a positive
وبعبارة أخرى، إذا كان هذا هو الفرق بين الحقيقة، فهذا مثال إيجابي
example and the likelihood that my model science to being a positive example.
واحتمالية ما يعينه النموذج كمثال إيجابي.
And we're going to weigh it by the feature value xj.
وسنوزن من خلال قيمة xj للميزات.
So this, for example, is the number of awesomes.
فهذا على سبيل المثال، هو عدد مرات "جيد".
So if later point has many awesomes,
لذلك إذا كانت هناك نقطة لاحقة بها العديد من "جيد"،
then it has more contributions of the the derivative because that coefficient's
فستساهم بشكل كبير في المشتق لأن ذلك المعامل
going to be multiplied by say 20 awesomes.
سوف يتضاعف لنفترض 20 مرة "جيد".
If you have zero awesomes, then there's no contribution here because weather
إذا كان لديك صفر "جيد"، فعندئذ لا يوجد أي مساهمة هنا سواء
the coefficient is high or low doesn't make any difference is the data point.
كان المعامل مرتفع أو منخفض لا يحدث أي فرق لنقطة البيانات.
So that's why we weigh that way.
ولهذا السبب نزن بهذه الطريقة.
So this is exactly the derivative that's very simple that we're going to implement.
هذا هو بالضبط المشتق البسيط للغاية الذي سنقوم بتنفيذه.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]